Guide to the Phi Kappa Phi - Montana State College Chapter Records 1921-1957
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Phi Kappa Phi - Montana State College Chapter records
1921-1957
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Phi Kappa Phi. Montana State College Chapter.
MSU.71007
2 linear feet
The Phi Kappa Phi - Montana State college Chapter Records consist of presidential records, membership lists and correspondence, records of awards programs and financial transactions. The records span the years 1921-1957.
The Honor Society of Phi Kappa Phi was founded in 1897 at the University of Maine, and is known as the oldest, largest, and most selective all-discipline honor society in the nation. The chapter at Montana State University-Bozeman was founded in 1921 and presided over by Dean E. B. Norris with the intent of bringing the benefits of the Phi Kappa Phi to Montana students and to continue the mission of the Society: "To recognize and promote academic excellence in all fields of higher education and to engage the community of scholars in service to others."
These records pertain to the establishment, operation and membership of the Montana State College chapter of the Phi Kappa Phi Honor Society. Included herein is an assortment of presidential records, membership lists and correspondence, records of awards programs and financial transactions. The records have been organized into three series dealing with executive operations, membership activity, and a limited number of financial transaction files.
Series 1 Executive records, 1921-1945
Series 2 Membership records, 1921-1955
Series 3 Financial records, 1929-1957
This collection is open for research.
Records of the MSC chapter of the Phi Kappa Phi honor society were accessioned by the University Archives in 1971. The records had likely been in the possession of Merrill G. Burlingame, but they had been subject to some water damage regardless of where they had been stored.
Montana State College--Students--Societies, etc.; Phi Kappa Phi-Montana State College Chapter-Archives
Montana; Bozeman (Mont.)
Greek letter societies--Montana--Bozeman (Mont.); Greek letter societies
Colleges and Universities; Montana; Bozeman
- Executive Records, 1921-1945; 1
  This series contains the constitution and manual of instruction for the chapter to supplement the initial by-laws and subsequent revisions. Also included are the president's annual reports from 1930 to 1943, and the minutes of chapter meetings spanning the years of 1921 to 1945. The contents are arranged by category and chronologically thereafter.
  - President's Annual Reports, 1930-1931; 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - President's Annual Reports, 1934-1945; 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - President's Annual Reports, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Deletions from President's Records (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Constitution and Manual of Instruction (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - By-Laws (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - By-Laws and Revisions (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1930-1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Membership records, 1921-1955; 2
  These records pertain exclusively with activities dealing directly with members. Boxes 2 and 3 contain all of the correspondence between the chapter and members from 1921 to 1944 in addition to folders dedicated to general notices and circulation letters. Box 4 contains both the records of membership from 1921 to 1955 and a collection of programs dealing directly with the members such as honors days, assemblies and banquets and awards certificates. Two folders contained in box 5 contain petitions started by members of the chapter. The records have been arranged by category and thereafter by date.
  - Correspondence, 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1928; 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Notices and Form Letters (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Circulation Letters (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Membership Papers, 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Membership Papers, 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Membership Papers, 1926-1929 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Membership Papers, 1930-1934 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Membership Papers, 1940-1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Membership Papers, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Membership Papers, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Membership Papers, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Membership (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Honor Society Bulletin (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Seniors' Honors Day (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Honors Society Programs (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Honors Day Assembly (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Certificates (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Banquets and Assemblies (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Drafts for National Journal (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Petitions, 1922-1930 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Petitions, 1922-1930 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Financial records, 1929-1957; 3
  Bank account records and other papers pertaining to the financial dealings of the chapter. There are folders for the National Secretary's records, the Treasurer's records, a comprehensive cash book and two folders dedicated to the receipts of transactions at the Commercial National Bank.
  - National Secretary (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cash Book, 1929-1957 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer's Records (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Commercial National Bank Receipts, 1942-1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Commercial National Bank Receipts, 1942-1949 (Box 5, Folder 7)